A Guide to the Executive Papers of Governor Thomas B. Stanley, 1954-1958
Library of Virginia
- Series IV General Correspondence:, 1954-1958., Extent: 19.95 cu. ft. (57 boxes). (Box Boxes 68-124)
  - Segregation, Pro-Integration, 1957 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Segregation, Interposition, 1956 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Segregation, Interposition, Senate Joint Resolution No. 3 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Segregation, Resolutions (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Social Security Board (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - Southeastern Interstate Forest Fire Protection Compact (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - Southeastern Conference on Education Beyond the High School Life (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Southern Governor's Conference, 1954 (Box 112, Folder 5-6)
  - Southern Governor's Conference, 1955 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Southern Governor's Conference, 1956 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Southern Governor's Conference, 1957 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Southern Governor's Conference, Segregation (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Southern Regional Council on Mental Health Training and Research (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, 1954 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, 1955 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, 1956 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, 1957 January-June (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, 1957 July-December (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, Atomic Nuclear Energy (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - Speeches, Governor's, 1954 (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Speeches, Governor's, 1955 (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Speeches, Governor's, 1956 (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Speeches, Governor's, 1957 January-June (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - Speeches, Governor's, 1957 July-December (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Speeches, Sent to the Governor (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Statements, 1954 (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Statements, 1955 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Statements, 1956 January-June (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Statements, 1956 July-December (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Statements, 1957 January-June (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Statements, 1957 July-December (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - States Rights (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Stirling, Mrs. Charles G. (Sarah V. Daingfield) (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Stonewall Jackson Memorial (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Stratford Journal (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - Strikes (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - Supreme Court Vacancies, Recommendations (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Taxes, Income (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Taxes, Misc. (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Taxes, Poll, Abolition of Poll Tax (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Telecasting (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Television (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Temperance (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Thanksgiving Celebration (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - Tickets, Requests for (Box 121, Folder 6)
  - Tidewater Auto Association (Box 121, Folder 7)
  - Tobacco Bowl Festival (Box 121, Folder 8)
  - Traffic, Highways (Box 121, Folder 9)
  - Traffic, Court Conference in Virginia (Box 121, Folder 10)
  - Traffic, Violations, 1954 (Box 121, Folder 11)
  - Traffic, Violations, 1955 (Box 121, Folder 12)
  - Traffic, Violations, Misc. (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Trial Justice's Conference, 1951-1953 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Trial Justice's Conference, 1954-1956 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Treaty, Lawmaking (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - Tuberculosis (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - Tusing, J.M. (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - United Nations Organization (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - Utilities (Box 122, Folder 9)
  - Valentine Museum (Box 122, Folder 10)
  - Veterans Administration Faculty (Box 122, Folder 11)
  - Veterans Affairs (Box 122, Folder 12)
  - Veterans, Bonus (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - Veterans, Disabled American (Box 123, Folder 2)
  - Veterans, Spanish-American (Box 123, Folder 3)
  - Veterans, Foreign wars (Box 123, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Conference of Social Work (Box 123, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Council on Health and Medical Care (Box 123, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Education Association (Box 123, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Federation of Garden Clubs (Box 123, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Foundation (Box 123, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Heart Association, Inc. (Box 123, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Highway Users Association (Box 123, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Historical Society (Box 123, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Inter-Agency Committee on Recreation (Box 123, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Manufacturers Association (Box 123, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Manufacturers Association (Box 123, Folder 15)
  - Virginia State Bar Association (Box 123, Folder 16)
  - Virginia State Teachers Association (Box 123, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Travel Council (Box 123, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Tuberculosis Association (Box 123, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Wildlife Federation (Box 123, Folder 20)
  - Voting (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - War Memorial Museum of Virginia (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - Washington War Memorial (Box 124, Folder 3)
  - Washington Governor's Conference file (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - "Welcome to Virginia" (Box 124, Folder 5)
  - White House Conference on Child Welfare (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - White House Conference on Highway Safety (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - World Peace (Box 124, Folder 8)
  - World Trade Conference (Box 124, Folder 9)
  - World War II Memorial (Box 124, Folder 10)
  - Young Democrats of Virginia (Box 124, Folder 11)
- Series V: Extraditions, 1954-1958., Extent: 5.95 cu. ft. (17 boxes). (Box Boxes 125-141)
  The Extradition records are housed in 17 boxes and are arranged alphabetically.
  - A-B (Box 125)
  - C-Co (Box 126)
  - Col-D (Box 127)
  - Do-Fa (Box 128)
  - Far-G (Box 129)
  - H-Her (Box 130)
  - Hew-Joh (Box 131)
  - Jon-Law (Box 132)
  - Lay-M (Box 133)
  - Ma-Mo (Box 134)
  - Mou-Pot (Box 135)
  - Pow-Rom (Box 136)
  - Roo-Sh (Box 137)
  - Shr-Stog (Box 138)
  - Stoo-Van (Box 139)
  - Vau-Williams (Box 140)
  - Williams-Z (Box 141)
- Series VI: Federal Government, 1954-1958., Extent: 2.1 cu. ft. (6 boxes). (Box Boxes 141-146)
  The Federal Government records are housed in 6 boxes and are arranged alphabetically by agency or subject. Subjects include: Army, Defense, and Executive Departments.
  - Army, Air Corps (Box 141, Folder 3)
  - Army, Camp Lee (Box 141, Folder 4)
  - Army, Camp Pickett (Box 141, Folder 5)
  - Central Intelligence Agency (Box 142, Folder 1)
  - Coast Guard (Box 142, Folder 2)
  - Commissions, Atomic Energy (Box 142, Folder 3)
  - Commissions, Civil Service (Box 142, Folder 4)
  - Commissions, Federal Communications (Box 142, Folder 5)
  - Commissions, Federal Power (Box 142, Folder 6)
  - National Committee for the Development of Scientists and Engineers (Box 142, Folder 7)
  - National Security Committee (Box 142, Folder 8)
  - Congress (Box 142, Folder 9)
  - Defense, Civil Defense Administration (Box 142, Folder 10)
  - Defense, Civil Defense Administration, Atomic Bomb Test (Nevada) (Box 142, Folder 11)
  - Defense, Secretary of (Box 143, Folder 1)
  - Defense, Selective Service (Box 143, Folder 2)
  - Defense, Service Discharge (Box 143, Folder 3)
  - Defense, United Service Organization (Box 143, Folder 3)
  - Departments, Agriculture (Box 143, Folder 4)
  - Departments, Commerce (Box 143, Folder 5)
  - Departments, Defense (Box 143, Folder 6)
  - Departments, Engineers, Roanoke River Basin Association (Box 144, Folder 1)
  - Departments, Health, Education, and Welfare (Box 144, Folder 2)
  - Departments, Interior (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - Departments, Justice (Box 144, Folder 4)
  - Departments, Labor, Commissioner of Conciliation (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - Departments, Navy, Deeds signed (Box 145, Folder 2)
  - Departments, State (Box 145, Folder 3)
  - Departments, Treasury, Defense bonds (Box 145, Folder 4)
  - Departments, War, Discharges (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - Departments, War, District Engineers (Box 145, Folder 6)
  - Departments, War, Flood Control (Box 145, Folder 7)
  - Disaster compact, J.H. Wyse (Box 146, Folder 1)
  - Employment Service (Box 146, Folder 2)
  - Forests (Box 146, Folder 3)
  - Information agency (Box 146, Folder 4)
  - Marines (Box 146, Folder 5)
  - Marines, Merchant (Box 146, Folder 6)
  - Navy, 5th Naval District (Box 146, Folder 7)
  - President (Box 146, Folder 8)
  - Presidential Inauguration (Box 146, Folder 9)
  - President's Committee on Education Beyond High School (Box 146, Folder 10)
  - Senate (Box 146, Folder 11)
- Series VII: Invitations, 1954-1958., Extent: 3.15 cu. ft. (9 boxes). (Box Boxes 147-155)
  The Invitations are housed in 9 boxes and are arranged chronologically.
  - 1954 January-June 15 (Box 147)
  - 1954 June 16-November 15 (Box 148)
  - 1954 November 16-1955 April (Box 149)
  - 1955 May-October (Box 150)
  - 1955 November-1956 May 15 (Box 151)
  - 1956 May 16-November 15 (Box 152)
  - 1956 November 16-1957 March (Box 153)
  - 1957 April-August (Box 154)
  - 1957 September-December (Box 155, Folder 1)
  - 1958 (Box 155, Folder 2)
  - Calendar (Box 155, Folder 3)
  - Time indefinite (Box 155, Folder 4)
  - To serve honorary position (Box 155, Folder 5)
- Series VIII: Miscellaneous, 1954-1958., Extent: 1.05 cu. ft. (3 boxes). (Box Boxes 156-158)
  The Miscellaneous records are housed in 3 boxes and contain personal correspondence and reprieves. Personal correspondence to Governor Stanley include: Watkins A. Abbitt, John S. Battle, Harry F. Byrd, Harry F. Byrd, Jr., A. Willis Robertson and William M. Tuck.
  - Personal correspondence, Abbitt, Watkins M. (Box 156, Folder 1)
  - Personal correspondence, Battle, John S. (Box 156, Folder 2)
  - Personal correspondence, Byrd, Harry F. (Box 156, Folder 3)
  - Personal correspondence, Byrd, Harry F., Jr. (Box 156, Folder 4)
  - Personal correspondence, Garber, John W. (Box 156, Folder 5)
  - Personal correspondence, Gary, J. Vaughan (Box 156, Folder 6)
  - Personal correspondence, Hardy, Porter, Jr. (Box 156, Folder 7)
  - Personal correspondence, Harrison, Burr P. (Box 156, Folder 8)
  - Personal correspondence, Jennings, W. Pat (Box 156, Folder 9)
  - Personal correspondence, Patterson, Bob (Box 156, Folder 10)
  - Personal correspondence, Robertson, A. Willis (Box 156, Folder 11)
  - Personal correspondence, Robeson, Edward J., Jr. (Box 156, Folder 12)
  - Personal correspondence, Smith, Howard W. (Box 156, Folder 13)
  - Personal correspondence, Stephens, A.E.S. (Box 157, Folder 1)
  - Personal correspondence, Tuck, William M. (Box 157, Folder 2)
  - Reprieves, Day, Earl (Box 157, Folder 3)
  - Reprieves, Green, Michael Robert (Box 157, Folder 4)
  - Reprieves, Tilton and Newman (Box 157, Folder 5-7)
  - Mimeographed letters (Box 158)